Finding Aid for W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute records, 1933-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute records 1933-1979
W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute.
87351 Bimu C124 2
Semi-autonomous institute concerned with graduate, postgraduate, and extension programs of the University of Michigan School of Dentistry; course outlines and enrollment lists, instrument lists, and topical files concerning conferences, workshops, and reunions.
5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came from the Institute (donor no. 7116 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute was a semi-autonomous institute concerned with graduate, postgraduate, and extension programs of the University of Michigan School of Dentistry. Shortly after its establishment in 1930, the W. K. Kellogg Foundation began the development of a health program whose purpose in part was to assist dentists in obtaining postgraduate instruction in the various phases of dental practice. Since the School of Dentistry had been offering postgraduate instruction for many years, the W. K. Kellogg Foundation began providing funds which amplified the teaching facilities of the School in an effort to meet the growing demands of the dental profession for postgraduate study.
The record group has been arranged into the following series: Course Outlines and Enrollment Lists; and Topical Files.
Subjects:
Dentistry--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dentists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. School of Dentistry.; W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute.
- Course Outlines and Enrollment Lists
  - 1933-1962 Enrollment Lists and Course Titles Only
    - 1933-1952 (miscellaneous and summaries) (Box 1)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 1)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 1)
    - 1938-1939 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 1)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 1)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 1)
    - 1942-1943 (Box 1)
    - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
    - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 1)
    - 1946-1947 (Box 1)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 1)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 1)
    - 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 1)
    - 1951-1952 (Box 1)
    - 1952-1953 (Box 1)
    - 1953-1954 (Box 1)
    - 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1)
    - 1957-1958 (Box 1)
    - 1958-1959 (Box 1)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - 1961-1976 Outlines and Enrollments
    - 1961-1962, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1962-1963, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1963-1964, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1964-1965, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1965-1966, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1966-1967, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1967-1968, 1 folders; 1 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1968-1969, 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1969-1970, 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1970-1971, 2 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1971-1972, 2 volumes (Box 3)
    - 1972-1973, 2 volumes (Box 3)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - 1975-1979 Outlines and Enrollments, interspersed
    - 1975-1976 (Box 3)
    - 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Instrument Lists, bound
    - 1960-1961 (Box 4)
    - 1961-1962 (Box 4)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 4)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 4)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 4)
- Topical Files
  - American Academy of Periodontists 1944-1967 Annual Conferences
    - 1944 (Box 4)
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1946 (Box 4)
    - 1947-1949 (Box 4)
    - 1950 (Box 4)
    - 1951-1955 (Box 4)
    - 1956-1959 (Box 4)
    - 1960 (Box 4)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 4)
    - 1966 (Box 4)
    - 1967 (Box 4)
  - Delta Dental Plan Consultants 9/1974 (Box 4)
  - Dental Materials Conferences, (under several titles) 1942, 1945, 1955-1966, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Kenneth A. Easlick Graduate (Periodontic) Society, Annual Conferences
    - 1957 and origins (Box 4)
    - 1958-1969 (Box 4)
    - 1971, 1975, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Society of Periodontists/19Detroit District Dental Society 1972-1975 (Box 4)
  - Michigan. University. Orthodontic Alumni, Biennial Meeting 1973-1974 and history (Box 4)
  - Michigan. University. Periodontal Alumni Association, Biennial Reunions 1971-1977 (Box 4)
  - Orthodontic Education 1958-1965 Conferences Teaching Endontics, 4/1965 Conference (Box 4)
  - Teaching of Dental Practice Administration 8/1963 Conference Program, Enrollment, Scattered Correspondence Papers, Proceedings, Summary, Notes, Reports (Box 4)
  - Royal College of Surgeons, Ontario 6/1974 (Box 4)
  - World Workshop/19Conference on Periodontics 6/1966 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
- Publications
  The W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute Publications series contains one subseries: Unit Publications. The Unit Publications subseries includes annual reports, brochures, bulletins of the graduate and postgraduate programs in dentistry at the University of Michigan, as well as the study documents of the Black Dentistry in the 21st Century conference. This subseries also contains programs and addresses created for the dedication of the W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute building. A report entitled Growth, Development and Health Problems in Dentistry: Questions and Answers is also found in this subseries.
  - Unit Publications
    - Annual Reports 1942/43-1947/48 (Box 1-P)
    - Brochures 1940-1986 (Box 1-P)
    - Bulletins (Course Catalogs)
      - Continuing Education Programs, 1979-1988 (Box 1-P)
      - Graduate and Postgraduate Dentistry
        - 1940/41-1947 (Box 1-P)
      - Graduate Dentistry
        - 1949/50-1990/91, 11 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Inter-American Post Graduate Course in Dentistry
        - 1943 1945-1946, 2 folders (Box 1-P)
      - Postgraduate Dentistry
        - 1949/50-1970/71, 5 folders (Box 1-P)
    - Conferences
      - Black Dentistry in the 21st Century, 1991 (Box 1-P)
    - Proceedings
      - Dedicatory Exercises of W. K. Kellogg Foundation Institute Graduate and Postgraduate Dentistry, 1940 (Box 1-P)
    - Reports
      - Growth, Development and Health Problems in Dentistry: Questions and Answers, 1948 (Box 1-P)